<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dataset on Albin Zeqiri</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/dataset/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dataset on Albin Zeqiri</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/dataset/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bumpy Ride? Understanding the Effects of External Forces on Spatial Interactions in Moving Vehicles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/bumpyride/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/bumpyride/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;bumpy-ride-understanding-the-effects-of-external-forces-on-spatial-interactions-in-moving-vehicles&#34;&gt;Bumpy Ride? Understanding the Effects of External Forces on Spatial Interactions in Moving Vehicles&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dl.acm.org/cms/10.1145/3706598.3714077/asset/e187b392-7df9-4257-a872-05c46cab7728/assets/images/large/chi25-985-fig1.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;As the use of Head-Mounted Displays in moving vehicles increases, passengers can immerse themselves in visual experiences independent of their physical environment. However, interaction methods are susceptible to physical motion, leading to input errors and reduced task performance. This work investigates the impact of G-forces, vibrations, and unpredictable maneuvers on 3D interaction methods. We conducted a field study with 24 participants in both stationary and moving vehicles to examine the effects of vehicle motion on four interaction methods: (1) Gaze&amp;Pinch, (2) DirectTouch, (3) Handray, and (4) HeadGaze. Participants performed selections in a Fitts’ Law task. Our findings reveal a significant effect of vehicle motion on interaction accuracy and duration across the tested combinations of Interaction Method × Road Type × Curve Type. We found a significant impact of movement on throughput, error rate, and perceived workload. Finally, we propose future research considerations and recommendations on interaction methods during vehicle movement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Eco Is Just Marketing&#39;: Unraveling Everyday Barriers to the Adoption of Energy-Saving Features in Major Home Appliances</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/ecomarketing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/ecomarketing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;eco-is-just-marketing-unraveling-everyday-barriers-to-the-adoption-of-energy-saving-features-in-major-home-appliances&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Eco Is Just Marketing&amp;rsquo;: Unraveling Everyday Barriers to the Adoption of Energy-Saving Features in Major Home Appliances&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cloudstore.uni-ulm.de/apps/files_sharing/publicpreview/8Kpe7gDXzLT99s6?file=/&amp;amp;fileId=140653206&amp;amp;x=1080&amp;amp;y=1920&amp;amp;a=true&amp;amp;etag=818affc28e8dcf3d6fd4f8ed383ee4ca&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;Energy-saving features (ESFs) represent a simple way to reduce the resource consumption of home appliances (HAs), yet they remain under-utilized. While prior research focused on increasing the use of ESFs through behavior change interventions, there is currently no clarity on the barriers that restrict their utilization in the first place. To bridge this gap, we conducted a qualitative analysis of 349 Amazon product reviews and 98 Reddit discussions, yielding three qualitative themes that showcase how users perceive, interact with, and evaluate ESFs in HAs. Based on these themes, we derived frequent barriers to ESF adoption, which guided a subsequent expert focus group (N=5) to assess the suitability of behavior change interventions and potential alternative strategies for ESF adoption. Our findings deepen the understanding of everyday barriers surrounding ESFs and enable the targeted design and assessment of interventions for future HAs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AutoTherm: A Dataset and Benchmark for Thermal Comfort Estimation Indoors and in Vehicles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/autotherm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/autotherm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;autotherm-a-dataset-and-benchmark-for-thermal-comfort-estimation-indoors-and-in-vehicles&#34;&gt;AutoTherm: A Dataset and Benchmark for Thermal Comfort Estimation Indoors and in Vehicles&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://viscom.publications.uni-ulm.de/api/uploads/251/teaser%20%283%29.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;Thermal comfort inside buildings is a well-studied field where human judgment for thermal comfort is collected and may be used for automatic thermal comfort estimation. However, indoor scenarios are rather static in terms of thermal state changes and, thus, cannot be applied to dynamic conditions, e.g., inside a vehicle. In this work, we present our findings of a gap between building and in-vehicle scenarios regarding thermal comfort estimation. We provide evidence by comparing deep neural classifiers for thermal comfort estimation for indoor and in-vehicle conditions. Further, we introduce a temporal dataset for indoor predictions incorporating 31 input signals and self-labeled user ratings by 18 subjects in a self-built climatic chamber. For in-vehicle scenarios, we acquired a second dataset featuring human judgments from 20 subjects in a BMW 3 Series. Our experimental results indicate superior performance for estimations from time series data over single vector input. Leveraging modern machine learning architectures enables us to recognize human thermal comfort states and estimate future states automatically. We provide details on training a recurrent network-based classifier and perform an initial performance benchmark of the proposed dataset. Ultimately, we compare our collected dataset to publicly available thermal comfort datasets.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
