<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ubiquitous Computing on Albin Zeqiri</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ubiquitous-computing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ubiquitous Computing on Albin Zeqiri</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ubiquitous-computing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Eco Is Just Marketing&#39;: Unraveling Everyday Barriers to the Adoption of Energy-Saving Features in Major Home Appliances</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/ecomarketing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/ecomarketing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;eco-is-just-marketing-unraveling-everyday-barriers-to-the-adoption-of-energy-saving-features-in-major-home-appliances&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Eco Is Just Marketing&amp;rsquo;: Unraveling Everyday Barriers to the Adoption of Energy-Saving Features in Major Home Appliances&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cloudstore.uni-ulm.de/apps/files_sharing/publicpreview/8Kpe7gDXzLT99s6?file=/&amp;amp;fileId=140653206&amp;amp;x=1080&amp;amp;y=1920&amp;amp;a=true&amp;amp;etag=818affc28e8dcf3d6fd4f8ed383ee4ca&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;Energy-saving features (ESFs) represent a simple way to reduce the resource consumption of home appliances (HAs), yet they remain under-utilized. While prior research focused on increasing the use of ESFs through behavior change interventions, there is currently no clarity on the barriers that restrict their utilization in the first place. To bridge this gap, we conducted a qualitative analysis of 349 Amazon product reviews and 98 Reddit discussions, yielding three qualitative themes that showcase how users perceive, interact with, and evaluate ESFs in HAs. Based on these themes, we derived frequent barriers to ESF adoption, which guided a subsequent expert focus group (N=5) to assess the suitability of behavior change interventions and potential alternative strategies for ESF adoption. Our findings deepen the understanding of everyday barriers surrounding ESFs and enable the targeted design and assessment of interventions for future HAs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Contextual Feature Combinations for Prediction of Subjective Thermal Perceptions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/thermalfeature/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/thermalfeature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;exploring-contextual-feature-combinations-for-prediction-of-subjective-thermal-perceptions&#34;&gt;Exploring Contextual Feature Combinations for Prediction of Subjective Thermal Perceptions&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cloudstore.uni-ulm.de/apps/files_sharing/publicpreview/7SyFePiCzcWioqc?file=/&amp;amp;fileId=140650255&amp;amp;x=3024&amp;amp;y=1964&amp;amp;a=true&amp;amp;etag=118823c4c39d8a15f83c1ad1adc54e50&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;Thermal attributes in the environment impact well-being, but their inclusion in standard well-being monitoring is challenging due to complex measurement requirements. Industry standards like the Predicted Mean Vote (PMV) index need numerous measures and specialized setups, making large-scale applications impractical. This study investigates predicting thermal perception ratings using only contextual factors. We conducted an ablation study using the Chinese Thermal Comfort Dataset (CTCD) and a Random Forest (RF) classifier to evaluate prediction performance with different contextual feature combinations on five labeling scales. Results showed that omitting measures required for PMV index calculation and relying on contextual features exclusively achieved F1 scores similar to those when including PMV measures. Key predictive factors included daily outdoor temperature and a person&#39;s clothing, weight, and age. These findings suggest that leveraging more accessible contextual data to estimate thermal perception ratings is promising, and further research should explore more contextual factors to enhance prediction accuracy and support well-being assessments.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
